Jerry D. House

Kansas City, Missouri

Phone: (816) 560-6214 | Email: <u>jdhouse27@gmail.com</u>

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/jdhouse1/ | GitHub: github.com/jdhouse27 |

Portfolio: https://jdhouse27.github.io/Portfolio/

Summary

Full Stack Web Developer with a background in healthcare, customer service, and retail. Leader by example with over 9 years of experience in technology, project management, and administrative positions. Effective at combining creativity and problem solving to develop user-friendly applications. Acknowledged by peers for attention to detail and determination towards successful project completion. Devoted to strengthening and refining professional effectiveness.

Technical Skills

Node.Js | Express | JavaScript | jQuery | React.js | React | GIT | GitHub | MongoDB | MySQL | Firebase | HTML | CSS | Bootstrap | Various CSS Frameworks | Media Queries | APIs | JSON | AJAX | Handlebars | Excel | Microsoft Suite | Heroku |

Projects

Scenic

Code: github.com/jdhouse27/Project2 | Demo: oneprotwo.herokuapp.com/

- Full stack application where a user selects a desired city, then the application would find something that interests the user. The user could then select to add to a custom itinerary for later use.
- Role: Project Lead Back-End Developer
- Tools: HTML5, CSS, UIKit, MySQL, Javascript, JQuery, Firebase, API, Express, Heroku, GIT

Fuel Me Now

Code: github.com/jdhouse27/Fuel-Me-Now | Demo:jdhouse27.github.io/Fuel-Me-Now/

- Application designed for users to locate local gas stations and purchase gas for delivery.
- Role: Front-End Developer
- Tools: HTML5, CSS, Javascript, JQuery, Firebase, API, GIT

Burger App

Code: github.com/jdhouse27/burger | Demo:eat-da-burger-jd.herokuapp.com/

- This application is for users to locate local gas stations and purchase gas for delivery
- Role: Full-Stack Developer
- Tools: HTML5, CSS, Javascript, JQuery, MySQL, Express, Handlebars, GIT

Bamazon

Code: github.com/jdhouse27/bamazon | Demo: jdhouse27.github.io/bamazon/

- Online store using Node.js and MySQL database and queries.
- Role: Back-End Developer
- Tools: Node.js, MySQL

On the Ropes

Code: github.com/jdhouse27/unit-4-game | Demo: jdhouse27.github.io/unit-4-game | |

- This application/game is a fun interactive game were users get to select a fighter and opponents to battle.
- Role: Front-End Developer
- Tools: HTML5, CSS, Javascript, JQuery

Professional Experience

Support Analyst - Retail Systems Management

April 2019-Present

- Troubleshoot issues, such as connectivity, hardware, or software issues ensuring successful and complete upgrade.
- Documentation of solutions through SharePoint
- Recover down machines due to failed Operating System image application.
- Reinstallation of Operating System, Printers, and other devices/software.
- Recover lost from network machines and reconfigure with correct IP address.
- Update/Resolve ServiceNow tickets.
- Ensure correct connectivity throughout new site cluster system setup.

General Manager/Owner Operator - Big Whiskey's

May 2017-March 2019

- Maximize staff effectiveness through strong sense of teamwork and purpose.
- Maintained employee schedules to effectively decrease labor by 8%.
- Increased sales by 15% through guest and employee satisfaction.
- Utilized Microsoft Office products to manage inventory data.
- Maintained a quality product while controlling inventory costs.
- Attained results through proper direction, inspiration, challenging, and engaging staff.

Application Support Analyst - Mosaic Life Care

April 2014-December 2018

- Built lab and pharmacy orders within Cerner applications per end user request.
- Created, updated, and resolved Jira work tickets.
- Troubleshoot issues in an analytical and logical manor.
- Wrote SQL queries for data retrieval.
- Collaborated with various departments for successful project management.

Respiratory Therapy - Mosaic Life Care

September 2009–April 2014

- Administered various Respiratory Therapies to patients.
- Promoted to shift leader within the first year.
- Educated patients, family members, and peers of respiratory care.
- Contributed to team meetings and collaborated with management in the decision-making process.

Education

Web Development | Coding Certificate: Kansas University, Overland Park, KS

A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Firebase, Node Js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js & ReactJS.

Respiratory Therapy: Concorde Career College, Kansas City, MO **Associates Degree and Certificate**